日本語字幕仕上げ：miraku  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
上げろ 椿！
ナツさん！
Natsu!
本能を貫けよ！ ストライカーだろ　お前は！
Follow your instinct! You're a striker, aren't you?!
ああっ！　惜しい～
Ah, so close!
It's not over, follow up!
まだだ！　詰めろ～！
クリア半端だ！ 前出せ　前！
That's not far enough, get it up front!
Akasaki! Let me shoot!
赤崎　俺に打たせろ～！
It's Natsuki! Lima, block him!
夏木だ！ 夏木を抑えろ　リマ！
…う しまっ…う！
Oh shi-
Yeah!
よっしゃ～　決めた～！
He scored!
ナイス　赤崎！　よくやった～！ 偉いぞ　お前！
Nice, Akasaki! Good job, man!
Zaki!
ザッキー！
How's that?! Did you see that?!
どうだ～！　見たか～！
Yeah! Great goal, Akasaki!
しゃ～っ！ よく決めてくれたぜ　赤崎！
これで　この試合 まだいける！
Now we're back in the game!
Zaki, nice goal!
ナイスゴール　ザキさん！
赤崎！
Akasaki!
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
For the right! Hold on tight!
hold on tight
my story…
My story...
forever
Forever...
赤崎！
They managed to grab a goal even with an iron-wall defense.
This is getting interesting.
We can do this, manager!
これは　いけますよ　監督！
Now, can ETU start to gain momentum?
That was a great shot!
いいねえ　お前のゴール
技ありっぽくて
So nice!
いいね～！
ジ　ジーノ…
G-Gino...
ったく…　向こうがクリアミスして くれたから　よかったものの
Geez.
It only went well because they weren't able to clear the ball properly.
We almost blew that chance.
もう少しでチャンスが ふいになるところだったよ
And that's after my loyal dog orchestrated a great attack,
せっかく僕の忠犬が いい形を作ったのに
ねえ　バッキー
Right, Baki?
Yes?
はい？
It's annoying when naive people do naive things, but
単純な人間が　単純な行動に 出るのは　不快だけど
if they're doing things half-heartedly, it's even worse.
単純な人間が半端な事をしようとするのは　もっと不快だね
僕と同じチームでいる以上
Since you're on my team, at least put in a bit more effort, Natsu.
せめて マシなほうでいてくれる事を願うよ　ナッツ
Gino... He's so stuck-up!
ジーノ…
偉そうに
Natsu, your shot was crucial.
ナツさんのシュートが効いたんだよ
Thanks to that, they focused on you, which created an opening for me.
あれで向こうが ナツさんを 警戒したから コースが空いた
アシストしてくれたようなもんスよ
So it was somewhat an assist.
赤崎
A-Akasaki!
But still, it only went in because of my skill.
ま　俺の技術だから 決まったんスけどね
よ～し！この勢いで もう１点取って　追いつこう！
Alright! Let's keep this up and grab an equalizer!
おう！
Yeah!
そうか　そうだよな
Right, that's it.
When I shoot, I'm also maximizing my teammates' potential!
俺がシュートを打つ事で　仲間を生かせる事もあるんだよな
監督の言う フォワードとしての 決心ってのが何なのかはよく分かんねえけど
Though I still don't know what the manager meant by "resolve as a forward",
I want to remain as a forward who always goes for the goal.
俺はやっぱり 常にゴールを狙うフォワードでいたい
というより… それ以外できる自信がありませ～ん！
Actually,
I'm not confident I could do anything but that...
I hope the manager isn't mad at me.
監督　怒ってなきゃいいけど
よかった～！ よかったよ　世良！
I'm so happy! I'm so happy, Sera!
な　何スか　気持ち悪い
What? That's creepy!
They finally managed to get one back.
何とか１点返したけどねぇ
残り２０分 ＥＴＵにとって厳しいのは ここからだ
20 minutes left. This will be really rough for ETU.
The dominant Osaka will definitely push for a win here.
試合巧者の大阪は 確実に勝ちにくる
Dulfer is making his move.
ダルファー　動きましたね
さあ　どうするんだ　達海？ あと２点
Now what will you do, Tatsumi?
Can you get two more goals against them?
もぎ取るだけの打つ手は あるのか？
Number 4, Ootomo. He normally plays as a defensive midfielder...
４番　大友
ポジションは主にボランチですね
It looks like Kubota's gonna be subbed off.
下がるのは…　窪田のようです
Alright.
うし
Kubota's going out.
窪田　交代や！
The excellent Kubota's getting subbed.
今日キレキレやった窪田が下がるぞ！
Well done, Kubota!
ええ仕事やった　窪田～！
Yeah! We're counting on you next time!
ホンマや！　次も期待してるぞ！
Though he didn't beat me,
自分が やられたからって訳じゃないが 本当にいいもの持ってやがる
he's really got something.
If this guy gets more experience,
こいつが経験ってものを兼ね備えたら
he might become a terrifying player.
いよいよ恐ろしい選手に なるかもしれない
Good job.
お疲れ！
あ…　はい
Man, it's so sad.
うう～　残念だな
友達がまだ遊んでるのに
It feels like being forced to go home while my friends are still playing.
先に家に帰る気分だ
窪田
You played very well, Kubota.
すばらしかったよ　クボタ
This is your best performance so far this season.
今シーズン一番の輝きだった
Uh...umm...thanks.
あ　え～と…　はい
体を休めつつ　ベンチから仲間の健闘を祈ってくれ
Take a rest on the bench and cheer the team on from there.
あ…　はい
Yes.
To be honest, I wanted to use him for another 10 minutes...
本音を言えば　あと１０分は 使いたかったのだがな
My best performance so far, huh?
今シーズン　１番の輝きか…
That was no good.
全然駄目だよな
When you don't play a full game, half the fun is gone.
フル出場しないと 楽しさ半減だ
やっぱりスタミナつけないと
As I thought, I really have to work on my stamina.
They have it good; they can still play.
いいなぁ
みんなはまだプレーできて
I'm envious...
いいなぁ
はっ　肝冷やしたぜ　窪田め
That Kubota had me sweating for a bit.
ヤツが　あそこまでやれる 選手とはね
I didn't think he was that good a player.
でも　この交代 我々の思惑どおりですね
It's going just as we planned, eh?
Kubota has never been a player who runs around to get the ball.
窪田は元々走り回って ボールをもらうタイプの選手ではない
Using Sugie who's an expert at man-marking against him
そこへ　１対１に強い 杉江を当てたのは
wasn't just to make sure he doesn't get the loose balls,
セカンドボールを拾わせないため だけではなく
it's also to wear Kubota out?
窪田自身の体力を 消耗させる狙いもあった？
窪田は杉江を翻弄した
Kubota got one over Sugie.
I wasn't expecting that, but that was a double-edged sword.
そこは計算違いだったけど
逆に功も奏した
Since he was upbeat, he was running more than usual.
好調がゆえに　プレーが乗れて
いつも以上に走り回った窪田は
But he ended up wearing himself out earlier than we expected.
こっちの予想より早く バテてくれた
Now Osaka's loose ball recovery rate will drop.
これで　大阪のセカンドボール奪取率は下がる
大阪ご自慢の　超攻撃的スタイルは その形を変えざるをえない
They now have no choice but to ditch their usual ultra-attacking style.
Shimura has pushed up now.
志村が１列前に来たか
タケシタツミ フォワードが１枚減ったくらいで
Tatsumi Takeshi,
If you think that we'll stop attacking just because we took off a forward,
我々が攻撃の手を緩めると 思ったら
you couldn't be more wrong.
大間違いだよ
Let's halt their momentum, Shimura.
ヤツらを　今一度 黙らせてやれ　シムラ！
ハン！ 目に物見せてやるよ　ダルファー！
Let me teach you a lesson, Dulfer.
They aren't committing many players for an attack.
なかなか攻めてこねえな
志村ほど　１試合を通して冷静でいられる選手は
There aren't that many players, like Shimura,
who're able to remain focused and calm throughout the entire game.
そうそういねえ
何を考えてやがる…　何を…
What's he scheming?
ふ～　なんか暑いなぁ
Why is it so hot?
I thought it'll be cooler at night so I wore long sleeves,
夜はまだ冷えると思って 長袖にしたけど
but you get hot when you run around.
やっぱり走ってると熱くなってくるなぁ
That's when you have to roll your sleeves up.
でも　そういう時は腕まくりだ
Though the bunched up part will be kinda uncomfortable,
まくった所がボワーッてなっちゃうけど
it still feels better than before.
今よりはマシな気がする
Adapting to situations like this,
こうやって状況に対応する
I bet that's how humans evolved.
きっと人間は こうして進化してきたんだろうな
What the hell is he babbling about?
何の話だ　おい！
Adapting to situations applies to soccer as well.
状況に対応するのは サッカーも同じだ
ETU's fast players are still full of energy,
ＥＴＵは　スピードのある選手が 元気だからね
so to do a counter will be hard.
ボールを奪われた時の カウンターが　やっかいだ
That's why you have to launch a simple attack...
だから確実な時に　人数をかけずに シンプルに攻めるべきなんだ
...without committing too many people.
They're using the flanks! Are they trying to beat us with speed?!
サイドから来た！　スピード勝負か？
いけ～　畑！
Go, Hatake!
Don't let ETU get cocky!
ＥＴＵなんか調子に乗らせんなよ！
There's not much time left. I'll just let Hauer grab the glory!
この際しゃあない
ハウアーに花持たせたるわ
決めろや　ハウアー！
Make it count, Hauer!
体ごと飛び込んでくるぞ！
He's jumping in with his whole body!
黒田！！
Kuroda!
弱い！
It's weak!
But it's heading for goal!
けど　枠行ってるぞ
Okay!
…よし
杉江～！ ナイスカバー！
Yeah, Sugie!
Nice cover!
Man, that was kinda dangerous!
なんか地味に危なかった！
杉江！
Sugie!
杉江！杉江！杉江！
Alright!
よ～っしゃ！
なんや　ハウアー！
What the hell, Hauer?! I expected more from you!
決め～言うたろが！
Haha, good one Sugie!
いいぞ　スギ
Nice clear!
ナイスクリアだ！
You've been irritating me all game!
Cut it out already!
Referee!
レフリー！
Hauer got a yellow card?!
ハウアーにイエロー
Hey, wait a minute! He should get one before me!
Let it go, Hauer!
やめとけ！　ええから　ハウアー
He ran into me first! Why do I get a yellow card instead?!
I understand how you feel.
お前の言いたい事　分かったから
ハウちゃん 今ごろ反抗期なのかなぁ
Hau-chan has entered his rebellious phase.
Nice, what a bargain.
よ～し　よし　もうけ　もうけ
I was right to pit Kuro against Hauer.
やっぱり　クロをハウアーにつけといて正解だったな
I didn't think he'd get that pissed.
あんなにイラついてくれるとは
I guess Kuro has a talent at pissing people off.
クロは人をイライラさせる 才能があるなぁ
Kuroda will be hurt when he hears that...
うっ！ それ聞いたら傷つきますよ　黒田
Well, I think it's time for us to make our move.
さ～て そろそろ　こっちも動くかい
Damn, my legs are worn out.
クソッ！ さすがに足にきてるな
I guess that can't be helped.
それもしかたないか
椿のケアで走りまくってるんだ
I had to run all game just to keep up with Tsubaki.
That run just then...
さっきの突破 ミーティングでは聞いていたが
I have heard about him during the meeting.
Seems like there's a real need to watch out for Tsubaki after all.
やはり椿は要注意人物だ
Once he gets going, he's unstoppable.
スピードに乗せると手がつけられない
Damn, it's in a weird place again!
また中途半端な所に
Tsubaki... I can't let him get the ball!
椿！　ヤツにボールを 渡すわけには！…
Wait, am I being forced to run?
あれ？ 走らされてるんじゃないのか？
マイボ　マイボ～
Our ball!
No way, that couldn't be...
まさか　そんなはずは…
Oh, ETU's making a change too!
おお！　ＥＴＵもカード切るぞ
Tanba is coming in for Kiyokawa!
清川に変えて丹波だ！
Alright. Good work, Kiyo!
お～し！　お疲れ　キヨ！
Leave the rest to me!
後は任しとけ
Okay.
ウス
オオトモ！　オオトモ！
Ootomo! Ootomo!
大友！
Good. Well done, Kiyokawa.
う～し　よくやったぜ　清川
ウス
Thanks.
Dulfer should have noticed by now.
本当は気づいてるはずだぜ　ダルファー
Well then, what are you going to do?
さ　どうするよ？
Tanba is going straight to the left full-back position.
丹波は　そのまま左サイドバックか
It seems like ETU have been concentrating their attacks on the left side.
今日のＥＴＵは　左での展開が 多いように思える
But Gino's passes are always being cut off by Hiraga's hard work.
でも ジーノのパスは 平賀のハードワークの 前では　カットされてばかり
So much that it seems unnatural...
それも　不自然なほどに
To be honest,
確かに 今日のジーノ
Gino has delivered some good passes, for someone who's not on form today.
不調にしては 要所要所で 光るパスを出していた
しかし　もし俺を走らせるのが 目的だとしたら…
But if he intended to make me run...
If he placed his passes right where Tsubaki and I have to battle for the ball...
俺と椿が　ちょうど競り合える所に ボールを出していたのだとしたら
it means that he...
今日のヤツは…
...might actually be on form today.
とてつもなく 調子がいい可能性がある
But then what's with that face?
いや
じゃあ　あの表情は何だ？
If he planned this, why would he look so displeased?
もし狙いどおりだったのなら
パスを出した後に　あんな 浮かない表情をするもんか！
Are you alright, Akasaki?!
大丈夫か　赤崎！
あ～　いってぇ～！
It hurts!
Man, this is tough.
いやぁ　参ったよ
When I first heard about this plan, I thought it sounded fun.
作戦を初めて聞いた時は 面白いと思ったんだけどね
But when I started doing it, problems began to surface.
いざやってみると 問題があってね
My pass completion rate goes down...
僕のパス成功率が 下がってしまうんだよ
...when I intentionally put them in weird places.
わざと半端な所に 出しているとね
It really frustrates me.
ホント　参るよ
As I thought, Gino wasn't having an off day.
やはりジーノは 不調ではなかった
He made that face because he was thinking about his pass completion rate.
あの表情は自分のパス成功率が下がるのを気にしてのものだったのか
Damn it, I was tricked!
クッ…　やられた！
It looks like even Hiraga is getting a bit tired.
あ？…　監督
Manager?
はっ おいおい　最初の元気は どこ行ったよ　ダルファー
Where is that spark you had at the beginning, Dulfer?
何か悩み事かい？
Are you worried about something?
Well, just stay that way.
悩め悩め　大いに悩め！
あんたが悩んでる　その時間こそ 俺たちの時間だ
The time you spend worrying will be our time to shine.
Oh, now I see! So that's how it is, Monsieur Tatsumi!
What?
Hmm, yes, I see.
The target's been Hiraga all along.
I knew he was plotting something.
I didn't think that the No. 10, Gino, would keep making the same mistake.
But, his purpose was to...
make use of ETU's speedy No.7...
to wear Hiraga out.
Hiraga is a player who believes in hard work
and he's willing to use up all of his energy in a game.
And so, by forcing him to keep running during the first half,
his energy allocation's messed up.
Disabling Hiraga's wide area of defensive coverage...
...basically means that ETU have conquered that part of the pitch.
How much stamina does this guy have?!
こいつ… どれだけスタミナあんだよ！
This is our chance!
よ～し　チャンスだ！
Sera!
世良～！
Oh, too bad!
あ～　惜しい！
It's still available! Go for it!
いける　いけるぞ！
Hey, what are you doing? Don't let them do whatever they want!
おい　何やっとんねん！ 好き勝手やらせんなっちゅうに！
It's true! Katayama has no choice but to go back to defend!
ホントだ！　片山は 守備に回らざるをえない
It's just like what the manager has said!
監督の言ってたとおりに なってきた
If that's the case, this could actually work!
こりゃ いけるかもしんないぞ
Monsieur Blanc,
then why not sub Hiraga off?
Against a fresh player, ETU would have a harder time, right?
That's the interesting part.
According to my information,
Hiraga has missed a few games due to suspensions or injuries,
but, other than that, he's never been subbed off since Dulfer took charge.
Osaka is a team where the starting players are fixed.
The substitution patterns are mostly fixed as well.
Instead of adapting to their opponent's playing style,
they stand by their philosophy.
It's a team that's as confident as Dulfer himself..
That's exactly the reason as to why they can't take out Hiraga.
Hiraga is their captain and, as such, he's irreplaceable.
He's the one who emphasizes Dulfer's ideals on the pitch.
You're too lax there! Focus!
Will he take out a player like him in order to win the match?
Or will they stick to their ideals that will go a long way in the future?
I believe Dulfer is having quite a dilemma.
The one's having a good time on the other hand...
...is Monsieur Tatsumi.
Oh, I see.
あ～　なるほど
うん 私の目に　狂いはなかった
I wasn't mistaken. You're an interesting man, Monsieur Tatsumi.
面白い男だ　ムッシュ　タツミ
Alright, we're almost caught up! Go ETU!
よ～し　あと一押しで 追いつけるぞ！
いけ～　ＥＴＵ！
Hey, Shige.
あのさあ　シゲちゃん
Huh?
It's stupid to just carry this thing, so how about holding it up?
これ　ずっと持ってんのもなんだし 手で揚げてみない？
Oh, sure. Let's do it!
おっ！　その手があったか
おし　やろうぜ！
I haven't seen it anyway.
俺　まだ見てねえしな
Does it say "Edo style fan troupe"?
「江戸前応援団」て入ってんのか？
Huh? No.
え？　違うよ
Does it say "Tatsumi" then?
じゃあ　達海の名前か？
違うよ
No...
あれ？
Tsu-Tsubaki?
つ…　椿かよ！
Well, there is no banner for him.
だって　あいつのダンマク 無いんだもんよ
But...
で…　でもよ～…
なんか　スゲエ選手に なる気がするんだよ　あいつ
I just get the feeling that he'll be incredible one day.
はぁ～　作っちまったもんは しかたねえか　…ったく
Since it's already been made,
こうなったら　応援するしか ねえじゃねえかよ！
we have no choice but to cheer for him.
だ～っ！　いけ～　椿！
Go! Tsubaki!
突っ走れ～　椿！
Go!
Tsubaki!
いけ～　椿～！
Go, Tsubaki!
Huh? Aren't those our dads?
あれ　父ちゃんたちじゃない？
Why are they holding a Tsubaki banner? I don't get it.
なんで椿のダンマク持ってんだ？
ワケわかんないな～
But, at this rate, Tsubaki might just create an opening. Well then...
けど　この勢いなら
確かに 椿がチャンス作ってくれるかも
Tsubaki!
椿！
Show us something special!
いいとこ見せろ！
Go!
いけ～！
Gino!
ジーノ！
I just need to shut this guy down!
起点のこいつを抑えれば！
You don't get it, there's no point in watching me now.
分かってないなぁ
今　僕の事　警戒したって 意味がないのに
Here, Tanbee!
はい　タンビー
Looks like we don't have that much time left.
さあて ぼちぼち残り時間も少ないぜ
Make this one count, Tsubaki!
この１本をモノにしろよ
椿！
Nice pass, Tanba!
ナイスパスだ　丹波！
Go, Tsubaki!
いけ～　椿～！
He's fast!
Wind? Or is it a torpedo?
風…
というか　突風？
Hiraga!
ヒラガ！
This will work!
いける… ナツさんか
Natsu?
Sera?
世良さん…
Or myself!
それとも　自分で…
Okay!
よし！
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say “never look back”
I'll say 「never look back」
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
そうchanceをのがすなら
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
no tears,Yes Let it go！
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough! Get tough!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
限界追い越せ
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
あすは見えない だから
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough!
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
共に乗り越えて 行け
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Stay cool!
We'll go!
予測できないだから
yosoku dekinai dakara
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
止められない
In order to catch up, we've got to exploit this.
How can we lose to you guys?!
We are out of time!
You're the only one who can settle this matter.
Maybe believing in a player like myself is fine after all!